George Lardner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Subject File, 1923-1997 (Box 1-285)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)
    - Casey, William J.
      - Senate inquiry
        - Research material
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973, 1981, undated, (2 folders)
    - Castro, Fidel, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Chile, 1970-1975, 1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - Church of Scientology, studies of bacterial warfare projects, 1980, (2 folders)
    - Colby, William E.
      - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1975-1983, undated
      - Research material, 1975, undated
    - Colson, Charles, 1974-1975
    - Constitutional rights, 1981-1982 (Box 19)
    - Copley News Service, 1973-1977, undated
    - Criminal conduct, 1975-1982
    - Defectors, 1981-1982
    - Demetracopoulos, Elias, 1975-1981, undated
    - Diplomatic cover, 1975, undated
    - Disinformation, 1981, undated
    - Drug smuggling, 1975
    - Drug testing, 1977, undated
    - Freedom of Information Act
      - General
        - Articles, 1976-1980
        - Research material, 1980-1981
      - Lawsuits, release of documents (Box 20)
        - Assassination Archives and Research Center v. Central Intelligence Agency, 1988
        - Center for National Security Studies v. Central Intelligence Agency, 1980-1982, (4 folders)
        - Halperin, Morton, Project on Freedom of Information and National Security (Box 21)
          - Articles and notes, 1975, undated
          - Research material, 1954-1975, undated
        - Miscellany, 1975-1982, (2 folders)
        - Washington Post Co. v. Central Intelligence Agency
          - Correspondence, 1981-1989, (2 folders)
          - Legal documents (Box 22)
            - General case material, 1981-1989
            - Indexes of documents released and denied, 1987-1988
          - Notes, 1981, 1987, undated
          - Research material
            - Congressional views, 1981-1982
            - Executive branch views, 1978-1981, undated
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1981-1987
            - Outside critics, 1981-1982
    - Goodwin, Richard, assassination plots in Latin America
      - Article, interviews, and notes, 1975
      - Research material, 1961-1963, (2 folders)
    - Helms, Richard, undated
    - Hughes, Howard
      - Glomar Explorer (submarine) and Project Jennifer
        - Articles, undated
        - Interviews and notes, 1974, undated
        - Research material (Box 23)
          - CIA documents, 1974-1977, undated
          - Global Marine Co., 1970-1974
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972-1981, undated, (2 folders)
      - Gonzalez, Virgino, and John Meier, 1971-1975, undated
    - Huminik, John, double agent, 1966-1967, 1977
    - Inman, Bobby R., 1981-1983, undated
    - Iranian hostages, failed rescue and security leaks, 1980-1982
    - Justice Department reforms of intelligence policy, 1978-1980
    - Labor party, 1975
    - Laws governing (Box 24)
      - American Bar Association, Standing Committee on Law and National Security, conferences, 1979-1980
      - Executive orders
        - Assassinations, 1989
        - Domestic espionage
          - Articles, 1981
          - Notes, 1981-1982, undated
          - Research material
            - Miscellany, 1981
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973, 1982
        - National Security Directive/Access to Classified Information
          - Articles, 1980-1982, undated
          - Interviews and notes
            - Justice Department proposal, 1980, undated
            - Miscellaneous, 1982, undated
          - Research material
            - Congressional hearings, 1982-1983
            - Executive order, 1951-1983, undated (Box 25)
            - Information Security Oversight Office reports, 1979-1982, undated
            - Miscellany, 1981-1983, undated
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1978-1983
        - Notification of Congress on covert actions, 1987
        - Overall activities, executive order 12333
          - Articles, 1981
          - Correspondence, Freedom of Information Act, 1981-1987
          - Interviews and notes, 1981, undated, (2 folders)
          - Research material
            - Executive order and miscellany, 1981-1982
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1979-1981
        - President's Oversight Intelligence Board, 1978-1981 (Box 26)
      - Legislation
        - Appropriations authorization, 1981-1989
        - Charter
          - Articles
            - Magazine, 1976-1980
            - Newspaper, 1979-1980, undated
          - Notes, 1970, 1979-1980, undated
          - Research material
            - Congressional hearing records, 1978-1980, undated
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1979-1980, undated, (2 folders)
        - Freedom of Information Act, 1974-1980, undated
        - Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (Box 27)
          - Article and notes, 1981
          - Research material, 1978-1981
        - Graymail legislation, 1980
        - Intelligence Activities Act (Aspin bill), 1980
        - Intelligence Identities Protection Act (names of agents)
          - Articles, 1981-1982
          - Correspondence, 1981-1982
          - Interviews and notes
            - Miscellaneous, 1981-1982, undated
            - Notebooks, 1982
          - Research material (Box 28)
            - Congressional hearing records, 1979-1982, (2 folders)
            - Legislation, 1980-1982
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1981-1982, (2 folders)
        - Intelligence Oversight Act
          - Article and notes, 1980
          - Research material, 1980-1981, 1987-1988
        - Intelligence Reform Act (Moynihan bill), 1980 (Box 29)
        - National Intelligence Act, 1980
        - Oversight of covert activities, 1978-1989, undated
    - Marchetti, Victor C., 1980, undated
    - Marks, John, 1975
    - McGehee, Ralph
      - Articles, correspondence, and notes, 1982, undated
      - Research material
        - Miscellaneous, 1977-1985, undated
        - Publication review, 1980-1982
    - Media
      - Congressional hearings, 1977-1978, undated
      - Prosecution for release of classified information (Box 30)
        - American Broadcasting Corp., 1984-1985
        - Dissident press and Angus Mackenzie suit, 1981-1982
        - Washington Post Co.
          - Articles, 1986
          - Interviews and notes, 1984-1986, undated
          - Research material
            - Boyce, Christopher, 1977-1985
            - Burt, Richard, 1982
            - Case law, 1949-1951, 1970, 1978-1985, undated
            - Casey, William J., remarks, 1986
            - Leaks, Libyan raid, 1986
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1950, 1975-1986, undated, (2 folders)
      - Recruitment, exploitation, and harassment (Box 31)
        - Articles and notes, 1982
        - Research material, 1974-1984, undated
    - Mind control, 1977
    - Miscellany
      - Articles and notes, 1986-1987, undated
      - Research material, 1964, 1971-1989, undated, (4 folders)
    - Montgomery, Hugh, 1981, undated
    - National Security Council, 1975, n.d
    - National Student Association, 1967, undated
    - Nicaragua (Box 32)
      - Notes, 1984
      - Research material
        - Guerilla handbooks, 1984, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1983-1985, undated
    - Oil production study, 1977-1978, undated
    - Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), 1981-1982
    - Poland, 1981-1982, undated
    - Police ties, 1981-1983
    - Political spying, 1983
    - Project Resistance, 1969, 1979, undated
    - Reagan, Ronald, administration (Box 33)
      - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1980-1981, undated
      - Research material, 1976-1980, undated
    - Reform efforts
      - Articles, 1976-1978, undated
      - Book proposal, 1982-1986, undated
      - Research material, 1977-1981, undated, (3 folders)
    - Rewald, Ronald, 1983-1984, undated
    - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, death penalty, 1953
    - Schlesinger, James R., 1975-1980
    - Snepp, Frank W., prepublication review (Box 34)
      - Articles, 1980, undated
      - Interviews and notes, 1980, undated
      - Research material
        - Congressional hearings, 1980
        - Legal documents and miscellany, 1964-1968, 1976-1980, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1977-1984, undated
    - Sources and methods, 1985-1986, undated
    - Soviets
      - Defectors
        - Other, 1964, 1971-1990, undated
        - Shadrin, Nicholas, 1981-1982, undated
      - KGB (Komitet Gosudarstvennoi Bezopasnosti), 1979-1990
      - Miscellany, 1985-1990
    - Turner, Stansfield, 1977-1983
    - United States House of Representatives (Box 35)
      - Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence
        - Central America, 1982
        - Establishment of committee, 1977
        - Hughes-Ryan rule debate, 1980, undated
        - National Intelligence Act of 1980 (Charter)
          - Articles and notes, 1979-1980
          - Research material, 1980, (2 folders)
        - Oversight of covert activities, 1980-1983
        - Physical searches, 1980
        - Publication review process, 1980-1981 (Box 36)
        - Soviet biological warfare, 1980
      - Select Committee on Intelligence (Pike Committee)
        - Adams, Samuel A., downgrades of Vietcong strength, 1969, 1975, undated
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1975
        - General
          - Articles, 1974, undated
          - Notes, undated, (2 folders)
          - Research material
            - Hearing records, 1975, undated
            - Newspaper clippings and related material
              - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976, undated
              - “Pike Report,” 1976
        - Hussein, King of Jordan, payments, 1977, undated (Box 37)
        - Iran, undated
        - Kissinger, Henry
          - Articles, 1975, undated
          - Notes
            - Hearings, 1975
            - Miscellaneous, 1975, undated
          - Research material, 1975, undated
    - United States Senate
      - Office of Classified National Security Information, 1976-1977, undated
      - Select Committee on Intelligence
        - Counterintelligence and security hearings
          - Articles and notes, 1990
          - Research material
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1990
            - Proposed legislation, 1990
            - Statements and testimony, 1990, (2 folders)
        - Establishment of committee, 1976-1977 (Box 38)
        - Freedom of Information Act exemption, 1982-1983
        - Kennedy, John F., assassination investigation, 1976-1977, undated
        - National Intelligence Act hearings (Charter)
          - Articles, 1980
          - Interviews, 1980
          - Notes, 1980
          - Research material
            - Analysis of key provisions, 1980
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1980
            - Statements and testimony, 1980
              - Feb.
              - Mar.-Apr., (4 folders) (Box 39)
        - Nicaraguan Contras, 1984
        - Press releases and miscellany, 1978, undated
        - Proposed abolition of committee, 1983
        - Proposed standing committee, debate, 1976
      - Select Committee to Study Government Operations with Respect to Intelligence Activities (Church Committee)
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, destruction of J. Edgar Hoover files, 1975
        - General
          - Articles, 1976
          - Correspondence and notes, 1976, undated
          - Research material
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1975-1976, undated
            - Printed matter (Box 40)
              - 1975-1976, (2 folders)
              - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 41)
        - Huston, Tom Charles, plan for domestic surveillance
          - Articles, 1975
          - Notes, 1975
          - Research material (Box 42)
            - Government documents, 1969-1975
            - Hearing records and newspaper clippings, 1973-1975
        - Justice Department investigation, 1975, undated
        - Mail intercepts
          - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1975, undated
          - Research material
            - Congressional hearing records, 1975, (2 folders)
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1975
        - Nixon, Richard M., deposition, 1976
    - Want ads (employment notices), 1990
    - Webster, William, 1988-1991
    - Wiretapping and electronic surveillance (Box 43)
      - Jabara, Abdeen, court case, 1979-1980
      - Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act
        - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1978, undated
        - Research material
          - Congressional hearings, 1978
          - Legislation, 1977-1978
      - Justice Department
        - Investigation report, 1976
        - Policy, 1975, undated
      - Miscellany, 1974, undated
      - Moss, John E., 1976-1977
  - Charities, 1979-1980, undated (Box 44)
  - China
    - Articles and correspondence, 1981-1990, undated
    - Notes, 1989, undated
    - Research material
      - Garrett, Banning N.
        - "The 'China Card' and Its Origins," 1983
        - "The Strange Basis for Learning in U.S. China Policy," 1989
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-1989, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1971-1988, (2 folders)
        - 1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Church, Frank
    - Articles, 1970-1976, undated
    - Correspondence, 1976
    - Interviews, 1975-1976, undated, (3 folders)
    - Notes, 1975, undated, (2 folders)
    - Research material
      - Campaign financing, 1974-1975, undated
      - Medical and financial reports, 1964-1975
      - Miscellaneous, 1970-1976, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - 1941, 1955-1969, (2 folders)
        - 1970-1976, undated, (7 folders) (Box 46)
  - Church of Scientology, 1976, undated
  - Civil Aeronautics Board, 1972-1974
  - Civil rights See also Container 149, Ku Klux Klan (Box 47)
    - Articles and notes, 1964, undated
    - Research material, 1964-1985, undated
  - Clark, Clifford, 1975-1977, undated
  - Cody, John Patrick (Cardinal Cody, Archbishop of Chicago)
    - Articles, 1981-1982, undated
    - Interviews, 1981
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1981, undated
      - Notebooks, undated
    - Research material, 1980-1981, undated, (3 folders)
  - Congo
    - Articles, 1978
    - Notes, undated
    - Research material
      - Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Austin, Tex.
        - 1960-1963
        - 1964-1967, 1977-1979, undated, (4 folders) (Box 48)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1963-1978
  - Corcoran, Thomas G., 1982-1986
  - Cuba
    - Articles and correspondence, 1980-1981
    - Interviews, 1981
    - Notes, 1980-1981
    - Research material
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1969-1970
      - Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Austin, Tex., 1964
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1976-1981
  - Dominican Republic, 1975, undated (Box 49)
  - Donovan, Raymond J.
    - In re Application for Appointment of Independent Counsel, 1984-1985
    - Articles, 1981-1987, undated, (8 folders)
    - Bergen Evening Record Corp., 1983
    - Checks, 1979-1980, undated
    - Correspondence, 1983-1987, undated
    - DeSapio, Carmine G., 1955-1984
    - In re Donovan (81-2) (Box 50)
      - 1982, (2 folders)
      - 1982 (Box 51)
      - 1983-1984, (2 folders)
      - 1986
        - Mar.-June, (2 folders)
        - July-Aug. (Box 52)
      - Undated
    - Donovan v. CBS, Inc., 1985
    - Donovan v. Merola, 1984
    - Ethics in Government Act, 1965-1987, undated
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation
      - Articles, 1982-1985, undated
      - Notes, 1983-1987, undated
      - Research material
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1978-1981, (2 folders)
          - 1982-1985, undated, (4 folders) (Box 53)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1981-1984, undated
    - Financial disclosures, 1981-1982, undated
    - Interviews, 1981-1982
    - Jopel Construction and Trucking Co.
      - Articles, 1981
      - Notes, 1980-1983, undated
      - Research material
        - General, 1977-1985, (2 folders)
        - Legal documents, 1980-1982, undated (Box 54)
    - Klepfer, Michael
      - Articles, 1983-1984
      - Notes, 1984, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1983-1984, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1983-1984
    - Masselli, William P.
      - Articles, 1981-1985, undated
      - Correspondence, 1981-1984, undated
      - Interviews, 1982-1985, undated
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1981-1986, undated
        - Notebooks, 1984
      - Research material (Box 55)
        - Legal documents, 1978-1985, undated, (4 folders)
        - Miscellaneous, 1976-1986, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1982-1984, undated
    - Minority Business Enterprise
      - 1980-1983
      - 1984-1985, undated (Box 56)
    - Nomination hearings, 1981
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous
        - 1982-1984, (4 folders)
        - 1985-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 57)
      - Notebooks (Box 58)
        - 1981
        - 1982, (2 folders)
        - 1982, (2 folders) (Box 59)
        - 1983-1984, (2 folders)
        - 1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 60)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1966-1970, 1981-1984, undated
    - Odierno, Salvatore
      - Articles, 1982-1983, undated
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1983-1986, undated
        - Notebooks, undated
      - Research material (Box 61)
        - Legal documents, 1983-1984, undated, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1982-1983
    - Operation Tumcon
      - Indexes to tapes, 1986, undated
      - Telephone logs, undated
    - Orlando, Michael
      - Articles, 1983-1984
      - Interview, 1987
      - Notes, 1983-1987
      - Research material, 1980-1985, undated
    - Payroll records
      - 1976-1977
      - 1978-1982, undated (Box 62)
    - People v. Donovan, 1984
    - People v. Schiavone Construction Co.
      - Notes, 1983-1985, undated, (4 folders)
      - Research material, legal documents
        - 1984, (2 folders)
        - 1984, (4 folders) (Box 63)
        - 1985
          - Feb. 6
          - Feb. 6, (3 folders) (Box 64)
          - Feb. 6 (Box 65)
          - Feb. 14
          - Mar.-Dec., (3 folders)
        - 1986
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 66)
    - Persico, Carmine, 1986, undated
    - Research material
      - Freedom of Information Act requests
        - Federal Election Commission, 1983-1985, undated
        - General, 1984-1985
        - Transportation Department, 1981-1985, (2 folders)
        - Urban Mass Transit Authority, 1975-1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 67)
      - Legal documents, 1978, 1984-1985, undated, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-1983, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related documents
        - 1980-1984, (3 folders)
        - 1985-1988, undated, (4 folders) (Box 68)
    - Sanzo, Louis, and Amadio Petito, 1983-1987, undated
    - Schiavone Construction Co. v. Merola, 1980-1986, undated, (3 folders)
    - Schiavone Construction Co. v. Montuorro, 1983
    - Schiavone Construction Co. v. Time, Inc., 1983-1985, undated (Box 69)
    - Silverman, Leon, 1981-1985, undated
    - Spying on the Senate Labor Committee
      - Articles, 1984
      - Interviews, 1984
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1982-1986, undated, (2 folders)
        - Notebooks, undated
      - Research material
        - General, 1982-1984, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984
    - Telephone numbers, 1982-1985, undated
    - Westway Project, 1981-1985
  - Druckman, Samuel, murder, 1935, undated (Box 70)
  - Employee Retirement Income Security Act
    - Articles, 1982
    - Notes, 1982
    - Research material
      - Legal documents
        - Backlog documents, 1979-1981
        - Committee documents, 1976-1981, (2 folders)
        - General, 1979-1981
      - Miscellaneous, 1977-1982
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1982
  - Energy bill, heating oil rebate, 1977
  - Espionage forfeiture bill, 1984-1986
  - Ethics in government
    - Ethics in Government Act, 1977-1981
    - Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (Box 71)
      - Notes, 1981, undated
      - Research material, 1976-1981, undated
    - General, 1965, 1986-1988, undated
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation
    - Allen v. FBI, 1979-1982
    - Charter legislation, 1978-1979, undated
    - Church of Scientology, break-in claims, 1976-1981
    - COINTELPRO (domestic intelligence program) (Box 72)
      - Albertson, William
        - Correspondence and notes, 1981
        - Research material
          - Miscellany, 1981, undated
          - Released FBI documents, 1962-1964, (2 folders)
        - Research material, 1975-1976
      - Chile Solidarity Committee of New York, 1975-1980, undated
      - Communist Party, 1956-1957
      - General
        - Articles and notes, 1977, undated
        - Research material
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1964-1978, undated
          - Released FBI documents, 1956, 1965-1974 (Box 73)
      - Mexico, 1961-1971
      - Operation Hoodwink, 1966-1968, 1975
      - United States Senate hearings
        - Articles and notes, 1975, undated
        - Research material, 1975-1976
    - Criminal undercover operations, 1978-1980, undated
    - Detention camps and national security index, 1971-1975
    - Domestic intelligence collection guidelines
      - Interviews and notes, 1983
      - Research material, 1976, 1983, undated
    - Electronic surveillance, 1975-1978, undated
    - Excludable aliens (Box 74)
      - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1978
      - Research material, 1963, 1972-1978, undated
    - Foreign intelligence collection guidelines, 1976-1980
    - Freedom of Information Act
      - Lament, 1981
      - Proposals to amend, 1979
      - United States House of Representatives hearings, 1976
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1942-1943, 1949-1954, 1983-1985
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, secret files, 1941, 1956, 1961-1966, 1971, 1975, (2 folders)
    - Illegal break-ins, 1975-1978, undated (Box 75)
    - Kennedy, Robert, and wiretaps, 1966
    - Lamphere, Robert, dispute concerning book on Julius and Ethel Rosenberg
      - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1977, undated
      - Research material, 1949-1955, 1975-1977, undated
    - Leaks, Ronald Reagan administration, 1983
    - Miscellany, 1975-1995, undated
    - Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, and warnings from Dusko Popov, 1941, 1982-1983
    - Political surveillance, class action lawsuits, Chicago, Ill., 1980-1982
    - Records management procedures, 1978-1986
    - Rowe, Gary T., Jr., murder allegations, 1977-1983
    - Socialist Worker's Party, undated (Box 76)
    - Terrorism, 1985
    - Tickel, H. Edward, break-in specialist
      - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1982-1983, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1979-1983, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1980-1983
    - United States v. Gray, pardons
      - Articles, interviews, and notes, 1981, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1978-1979
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1980-1982
    - Webster, William, 1980-1982 (Box 77)
    - Weisberg, Harold, Freedom of Information Act petitions, 1983-1985
  - Federal Election Commission, 1977-1985, undated
  - Fisher, George A., 1966, 1972, 1986
  - Floodgate (Daniel J. Flood)
    - Airlie Foundation
      - Articles, undated
      - Correspondence, 1978, undated
      - Notes, 1978, undated
      - Research material
        - Distant Drummer investigation, 1970
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1960, 1966-1969, (2 folders)